<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2024new</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/29/2024new/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/29/2024new/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally got straight A+ in 23 fall…. ;) It was not easy for me, I am not a great test taker… My favorite course, CS:APP, I was just A-.</p><p>I had arrived at Berkeley and was busy with course selection and various other matters. In addition, I was also looking for research. I was very, very busy. I took EECS151, EECS151LA, EE140 and MSE243. These are very challenging and I hope to have a good result.</p><p>顺带一提，数据结构，CSAPP，计组和EDA的资料整理又得延后了，或许会在这学期结束后和UCB的EECS151&amp;EE140一起整理发布出来。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>chat</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2023final</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/02/2023final/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/02/2023final/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You are welcome to cite my ECG conference articles. Articles from IEEE Sensors Journal have also been accepted and are waiting for publication.</p><p>I have been very busy recently looking for Berkeley research groups and final review &amp; papers. I will publish another MIA in the near future(Lei’s group), about feature extract processing of large models in medical image processing. I will go to UCB for a semester as an visiting student after January 16th. I hope everything goes well.</p><p>最近忙于寻求Berkeley的课题组和期末复习＆论文，非常忙，近期我正在努力向MIA靠拢，关于医学图像处理方面，大模型的feature extract处理。1月16日后我会前往UCB交换一学期，希望一切顺利。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>2023fall</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>davis2</title>
    <link href="/2023/08/07/davis2/"/>
    <url>/2023/08/07/davis2/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What makes me strange is that people here seem to use matlab, don’t know much about python format, and even jupyter code is not familiar… This forces me to go back to learn matlab syntax, but I also think this is really useful of.</p><p>慢慢地跑一些Monte Carlo模拟，这里的空调真舒服~</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>2023davis</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>davis1</title>
    <link href="/2023/07/30/davis1/"/>
    <url>/2023/07/30/davis1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is very common that I rush to make PPT before the group meeting… To be honest, I still like the life here in Davis, it is very peaceful and beautiful, and people are very friendly. But because of my personality, I always like to plan and think about many things, which doesn’t seem to fit well with the quiet pastoral life… If possible, I still hope to live here forever.</p><p>And one more thing is, MY SPEAKING IS SO BAD…XD</p><p>如果能重来，我要好好学口语~</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>2023davis</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>plan</title>
    <link href="/2023/07/20/plan/"/>
    <url>/2023/07/20/plan/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My computer mainboard burnt out, and there was no place for repairs in Davis. I had no choice but to buy another laptop here. Most of my files can be recovered, but I lost my previous blog files, and the backup was on my lab computer. I won’t be able to go back for two months, so I plan to rebuild my blog.😔</p><p>Next, I will continue to update this blog, including the notes on CSAPP and Data structures that I have been wanting to update since last year, as well as the notes on Computer Organization and Design for this semester. Afterward, I will focus on research and applying for a Ph.D. program in ECE in the United States.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>chat</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>world!</title>
    <link href="/2023/07/17/world/"/>
    <url>/2023/07/17/world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello! This is Yu Li, a student from WHU and attempting to explore more!</p><img src="/2023/07/17/world/230717.jpg" class="" title="UC Davis sunset">]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>chat</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
